const mcqs = [
  {
    section: "A",
    question: "The element having no neutron in the nucleus of its atom is",
    options: ["Hydrogen", "Nitrogen", "Helium", "Boron"],
    answer: "Hydrogen",
  },
  {
    section: "A",
    question: "Example of super octet molecule is :",
    options: ["SF6", "PCl5", "IF7", "All of these"],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    section: "A",
    question: "Correct order of bond energy of C–O bond is :",
    options: [
      "CO3^2- > CO2 > CO",
      "CO2 > CO > CO3^2-",
      "CO > CO2 > CO3^2-",
      "None of these.",
    ],
    answer: "CO > CO2 > CO3^2-",
  },
  {
    section: "A",
    question:
      "Arrange the following ions in the order of decreasing X–O bond length where X is the central atom",
    options: [
      "CIO4^- , SO4^2- , PO4^3- , SiO4^4-",
      "SiO4^4- , PO4^3- , SO4^2- , CIO4^-",
      "SiO4^4- , PO4^3- , CIO4^- , CIO4^2-",
      "SiO4^2- , SO4^2- , PO4^3- , CIO4^-",
    ],
    answer: "SiO4^4- , PO4^3- , SO4^2- , CIO4^-",
  },

  {
    section: "A",
    question:
      "Which of the following overlaps gives a sigma bond with x as internuclear axis?",
    options: ["pz and pz", "s and pz", "s and px", "dxy^2 and dxy^2"],
    answer: "s and px",
  },
  {
    section: "A",
    question: "The structure of F2SeO is analogous to :",
    options: ["SO3", "CIO3^-", "XeO3", "(B) and (C) both"],
    answer: "(B) and (C) both",
  },
  {
    section: "A",
    question: "In which of the following N is in the sp2 hybridisation state",
    options: ["(CH3)3N", "CH2 = NH", "CH3CN", "NO2+"],
    answer: "CH2 = NH",
  },
  {
    section: "A",
    question: "In H2SO4 molecule",
    options: [
      "S-atom is sp3d2 hybridised and there are 4 lone pair electrons on ‘O’ atoms.",
      "S-atom is sp3 hybridised and there are no lone pair of electrons in the molecule.",
      "S-atom is sp3 hybridised and there are 8 lone pair electrons on the ‘O’ atoms.",
      "S-atom is sp2 hybridised and these are 8 lone pair electrons ‘O’ atoms",
    ],
    answer:
      "S-atom is sp3 hybridised and there are 4 lone pair electrons on ‘O’ atoms.",
  },
  {
    section: "A",
    question:
      "In which of the following pairs hybridisation of the central atoms are different ?",
    options: [
      "ClF3 , ClF3O",
      "ClF3O, ClF3O2",
      "[ClF2O]+ , [ClF4O]-",
      "[ClF4O]- , [XeOF4]",
    ],
    answer: "[ClF4O]- , [XeOF4]",
  },
  {
    section: "A",
    question:
      "All the following species have all their bond lengths identical except :",
    options: ["AsF3", "AsF4^-", "AsF4+", "AsF6^-"],
    answer: "AsF3",
  },
];
export default mcqs;
